Contact

780-966-2257 (Mobile) churchmf@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/churchmf (LinkedIn)

matthewchurch.ca (Personal)

Top Skills

Game Development

C++

C#

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) French (Limited Working)

Certifications

Software Product Management Specialization

Docker Technologies for DevOps and Developers

Introduction to User Experience Design

Virtual Reality Overview for Developers

Publications

ScriptEase II: Platform Independent Story Creation Using High-Level Patterns

Presentation: Enhancing Telemetry Context With Video

Presentation: Improving Content Creator Workflow and Ensuring Quality with Big Data and Video

Presentation: Improving Workflow and Ensuring Quality with Big Data and Video

A Demonstration of ScriptEase II

Patents

Synchronized Video with In Game Telemetry

Matthew Church

Programmer and Independent Game Developer Edmonton, Alberta, Canada

Summary

Experienced, passionate, and accredited Software Developer with a focus on user-experience, web, games, and tools development. C#, Python, Angular, and C++ programmer with knowledge in operating systems, algorithms, and web development. Bachelor of Computer Science accredited on multiple video games ranging from AAA sport titles to epic role playing narrative adventures. Versed in game design and computer graphics concepts. Tools developer with knowledge in database integration, data processing, user interface design, software testing and quality analysis.

Shipped titles:

FIFA 13

FIFA 14

FIFA World Cup 2014,

Dragon Age Inquisition,

Mass Effect Andromeda.

Anthem

Experience

Serious Labs Inc.
Senior Programmer
June 2018 - Present
Edmonton, Canada Area

Collaborated with art, design, production, and quality assurance to create virtual reality training simulators in Unity. Met with stakeholders across the team to improve workflow and develop tooling to facilitate content creation and project scalability. Programmed player movement models, fixed project wide bugs, and ran seminars teaching best practices.

Bioware Software Developer June 2014 - June 2018 (4 years 1 month)

Edmonton, Canada Area

Designed and implemented company wide internal web applications in an agile team. Expanded scalable and intuitive tools utilized by dozens of game teams and occupations including programmers, designers, testers, and managers. Improved existing workflows by integrating web applications with game engine and development tools. Experience leading small development team in agile planning and delivering software on time and quality. Lead design meetings and meet with users to improve existing systems.

Electronic Arts (EA)
Software Engineer
July 2013 - June 2014 (1 year)
Vancouver, Canada Area

Full time engineer on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Working extensively with producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Participated in agile sprint planning in a large team in order to meet deliverables on a deadline. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and ActionScript in a massive code base.

Electronic Arts (EA)
Associate Software Engineer
January 2012 - September 2012 (9 months)
Burnaby, Canada

producers, quality assurance and other engineers to deliver high quality features for the game. Took ownership of several features both

Internship on the FIFA Games Mode Team. Worked extensively with

new and old. Tested, wrote and debugged C++ and SQL in a massive code base.

University of Alberta Software Engineer Intern May 2010 - September 2011 (1 year 5 months)

ScriptEase Research Project. Developed and implemented extendible tools in a team environment which allow users to script video games without any programming experience. Attended weekly meetings emphasizing scrum planning, feature development and brainstorming. The code base grew to just over 12,000 lines during my time on the project.

Education

University of Alberta

BSc, Computing Science Specialization \cdot (2007 - 2013)